

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211









PMP, Vice President seeking roles in Program Management, Business Analysis, Portfolio Management, Partner Management, Product Management, Demand Management, Release Management, Resource Management, Business Continuity, Capacity Planning, Risk Management



Current Designation: Vice President - Demand Management Total Experience: 21 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Asia & EMEA

Current Company: Citibank

Current Location: SINGAPORE

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Chennai. Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO Industry: Banking/Financial Services/Broking

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Vice President, Head/VP/GM, Program Management, Business Analysis, Portfolio Management, Partner Management, Product Management, Demand Management, Release Management, Resource Management, Business

Notice Period: 1 Month

TECHNOLOGY]

Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [INFORMATION

Continuity, Capacity Planning, Risk Management, PMP

Last Active: Oct-Dec 2020

Last Modified: Oct-Dec 2020

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education |

Summary

Global Operations & Technology Leader, certified PMP & Six Sigma Green Belt professional, specialized in governance (Programme and Project Offices), Demand Management and Release Management practices. Over 19 years of experience in banking & software product companies in various roles including Demand Management, Release Management, Program Management, Project Management, Business Analysis and Delivery roles with creativity and passion for problem solving, knowledge sharing and continuous improvement.

Work Experience

CITIBANK as Vice President - Demand Management Asia & EMEA Dec 2015 to Dec 2020

Vice President - Demand Management Asia & EMEA since Dec 15 date Reporting to Business Management Head for Asia & EMEA, I am responsible for Demand Management function to drive planning & prioritization of IT demand coming from Consumer businesses across 17 markets & ensure optimum utilization of planned capacity.

Provided leadership for Technology Investment Planning practice for Asia Consumer business, partnering with Finance and Business leads for Big Data, Cards, Retail, Digital, Operations, Compliance, Country technology and Global teams like Fraud, Data Governance, Risk/AML. Defined reporting for plan consumption tracking against plan. Overall plan exceeding \$250MM

In close partnership with Human Resource Managers, manage planning for 3200+ technology resources across multiple teams serving from multiple locations. Partner with Business Heads/Leads for optimum resource allocations across different technology areas, yet ensuring capacity levels are maintained to meet ever fluctuating business

Work with Regional Business Portfolio owners to manage business demand for Quarterly Releases, each accounting for approximately 160 Mman days of work

Enforced discipline in tracking each Quarterly Release within team and established standards for reporting & communication to various Business and Technology stakeholders

Extensive Reporting to support management in quarterly Regional Prioritization Councils, Monthly Operating Reviews, Country Business Managers reviews as well as attending to adhoc reporting needs from Global verticals

Developed and championed tracking mechanism for accurate tracking of project cost allocations to cost centres encompassing challenge for projects impacting multiple geographies

Coached team members to ensure adaptability to evolving needs in evolving business environment

Vice President - Release Management Head - EMEA Jan 14 - Dec 15 Reporting to Asia & EMEA Demand & Release Head, led Release Management function for EMEA Consumer: Led Deployment of Monthly Releases for EMEA consumer Cards & Retail businesses across 5 EMEA markets. Average quarterly deployment of approx. 30K man days of development work across teams covering various technology

stacks and geographies



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Provide Release Governance across Design, Development, Testing & Implementation phases to quarterly releases comprising of projects approved by Regional Prioritization Committee

Engaged development teams to determine inter-project dependencies, providing RAG status at Release level, review individual projects against Release milestones to ensure ONE deployment for all projects catering to different needs of EMEA Consumer business across Cards & Retail areas

Led Implementation planning in close engagement with Change Management Groups, coordinating UAT signoffs across all projects with Testing Centre and defining the downtime heatmap during the implementation, and ensuring timely resolution of issues caused by implementation

Define & deliver Release Dashboards to all key stakeholders

Vice President - Regional Relationship Manager - EMEA

Nov 11 - Dec 13

Managed team comprising of Relationship/Project Management Team for supporting Credit Cards businesses across EMEA region:

Manage Credit Card Application Product Releases across 14 EMEA countries leading team of relationship managers & project managers

Led Divestitures projects for over 15 EMEA business portfolios sold by Citi as part of Citi Holdings strategy

Asst. Vice President - Relationship Management & Project Management - EMEA Feb 07 - Oct 11

Accountable for quality delivery for a suite of Credit Card applications by providing leadership, functional expertise and guidance to a team of IT professionals. End-to-end oversight of all development projects from requirements to implementation and ultimately on-going support

- Citibank as Vice President Demand Management Asia & EMEA Feb 2007 to Till Date
- Kanbay Software Exports Pvt. Ltd. as Program Manager Oct 2005 to Feb 2007

Initiated & Championed Program Management practice in the organization Program Management for HSBC yearly release called GOLD Test Integration Management for several critical projects Initiated & Championed Knowledge Management Initiative practice in the organization Won various recognition awards within one year in organization

Birlasoft Limited India as Project Manager & Test Lead

Mar 2003 to Oct 2005

Managed Application Support Group (Production Support) for GE SBI credit cards supporting over 50 applications on various technologies

Conceived & developed prototype for TATA SBI Cards Customer Service Application Portal & implemented in short timeframe to support timely business launch

Project Test Manager for Testing Projects in Vision Plus for GE Australia Credit Cards including "Sales Finance Credit Line Data Mgration" project of 1.82 million Credit Cards from Westpac ICBS platform to GE's Vision PLUS platform in Australia & implementation of fraud detection product "Falcon"

Six Sigma Green Belt Certification & mentored 3 Green Belt projects

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.A (Hons. Mathematics) from Delhi University - Sri Venkateswara College in 1998

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY) from Karnataka State Open University (KSOU) in 2001

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

PMP

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Punjabi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.